"Previously on The Mentalist..."
Listen, there's this poker game
we've got going on.
- You want in?
- Maybe. When?
Let me see. Thursday night.
You're going to play poker.
Hey. Teresa.
Glad you made it.
- This is district attorney Don Wolcott.
- Hi.
FBI Bureau Director
Charles Bailey.
- Sir.
- Senator Eileen Dawkins.
State Senator.
It's a pretty high-class crowd.
I wish you would have warned me.
Oh, I think you know
this guy, right?
Teresa. I didn't take you
for a gambler.
It's not gambling if you know
you're gonna win.
Ace of hearts.
Not me.
Action's on you, Judge.
Well...
$500.
Dealer folds.
That's $500 more to you, Bertram.
Raise it $1,000.
You're bluffing.
All in.
I love playing with you, Gale.
I can read you like a kids' book.
- Yeah, yeah. Just pick up your chips.
- "Goodnight Moon."
Ay, yi, yi.
- I'm sorry guys, but we caught one.
- Okay.
- Will you cash me out?
- Yeah.
Have fun.
There you are.
I should come by sometime
when there's not a corpse here
to meet us.
Are you playing poker again, Lisbon?
It's getting the better of you.
- Losing money?
- Losing skin's more like it.
Bertram's been in a bad mood.
Hi. I'm Agent Lisbon
with the CBI.
Christos Papadakis.
I am Dean of the university's
Natural Science Department
so... the museum
is my responsibility.
Please follow me.
I believe your team is the one
who investigated the death
of Professor Montero.
Yeah, we were.
We have a bit of a walk.
The museum labs are
in the east wing of the museum.
What can you tell us
about the victim?
- We think it is Linda Parfrey.
- You think it's her?
Linda has been missing
for some time, and...
Well, you'll see.
Ah, this is the student who found Linda.
Tell...tell them your name.
Uh, Greg.
Uh, Gregory Lewis.
I found her around midnight.
Tell me what happened.
Well, by sheer luck, I-I happened upon
a very nice tree shrew.
I've never examined one before
and I-I brought it in to
strip the flesh off.
You know,
to keep the skeleton.
- How do you do that?
- Oh, we put 'em in these tanks.
How does that strip them
of their flesh?
- Flesh-eating bugs.
- Flesh-eating bugs. Right.
Right.
That's when I found Linda.
Okay.
- Yeah, that's Linda's ring, all right.
- So it is Linda Parfrey.
Why dump a body
into a beetle tank?
The museum doesn't have
great security
but it's not the kind of place
you can sneak a body out of.
Unless you make it small enough
to fit in a duffel bag.
So the killer was waiting
for the bugs to eat it
down to the skeleton
so they could sneak it out?
Possibly. Uh, we found
a scientific tool in the tank.
It could be the murder weapon.
So the killer's probably
another scientist then.
Or someone that works at the museum.
When was Linda last seen?
Linda's been missing
a couple weeks.
People thought she was
out camping near Yosemite
doing some kind of research.
Then someone noticed
her car was on campus
and they realized
she was missing.
- "Who filed the missing persons report?"
- Dr. Sonia Kidd.
Head of the biology department
at the university and Linda's adviser.
Her name sounds familiar.
Yeah, she's written a couple books.
Popular science stuff.
One's called
"Natural Born Killers:"
"The Evolutionary Roots of Murder."
Cute. Jane and I will go talk to her.
And, uh, Linda had an office
here at the museum.
- You and Cho check it out.
- You got it, boss.
We thought she was lost
in the mountains.
But she was here
the whole time.
It's too horrible for words.
What did she study?
What kind of animal?
Why does that matter?
Nobody picks what they dedicate
their life to by accident.
It says something.
I study primate brains.
What does that say about me?
You have dark thoughts
inside your head
that you want to believe
are normal and natural.
Which they are, of course.
Linda was an ornithologist.
Her doctorate was on the diet
of the northern flicker.
A kind of woodpecker.
Interesting.
Tenacious.
Bang their head against the problem
until they solve it.
- Was that Linda?
- It was.
Although woodpeckers
don't bang their heads against things
so much as they use their bills
to drill holes.
Yes. Well, the subconscious mind is...
isn't really a stickler
about that kind of thing.
Was she a good student?
Brilliant.
She had already co-authored several papers
in prestigious journals.
- Well, who was jealous?
- Nobody.
This is the top biology department
on the West Coast.
Best and brightest only.
The success of one of us helps all of us.
We're a family.
Well, people murder family members
every day. It's natural.
Murder is natural.
But abnormal.
Teachers don't know there's scandals
unless of course they are the scandal.
Are we done?
Yeah. For now. We're gonna
need to talk to some students
and visit the gift shop
which is left out the door, isn't it?
Yes.
Excuse me.
What are you doing?
- Who are you?
- I'm Agent Rigsby. This is Agent Cho.
- We're with CBI. And you are?
- Megan Parker.
I was Linda's classmate
in the doctoral program.
- And I have the office next door.
- What are you doing here?
I just came to get my copy of
"Understanding Macro-Evolution"
before you guys
sealed the place off.
- Did you know Linda well?
- She was rock star.
A rock star who could use
a makeover, but still.
She got the Dean's fellowship
this year.
That's like 100 grand.
The rest of us will be
paying off our student loans
with our social security checks.
What's with all the taxidermy?
I thought Linda just studied
woodpeckers.
No, Linda managed
the specimen rooms
for her work-study,
so she got the overflow.
Drugs?
- Sugar.
- She didn't do drugs.
Not even diet soda.
What about
her personal life?
- What about it?
- Did she have one?
We didn't talk about
that stuff very much.
I know she had a boyfriend
outside the school.
But that's all I know.
Hey, Jane, call me when you get this.
I think I found
Linda's classmates.
Look for the elephants.
Most species stay in stasis
for long periods of time.
- Sorry, can I help you?
- I'm Agent Lisbon with the CBI.
Professor Friedman?
Adjunct Professor.
Yes, adjunct Professor
Paul Friedman
which, as you can see, engenders
a great deal of respect
from the students.
Uh, I teach a couple seminars
under Dr. Kidd.
I'm sorry to interrupt
but I'm looking for information
on Linda Parfrey.
- These are her classmates, right?
- Yeah. We all know Linda.
Do you know anything that might be
helpful with the investigation?
We know that Linda had a boyfriend.
We'd like to talk to him.
Ex-boyfriend, I guess.
She didn't talk much about it,
but late one night in the lab
she told me they broke up.
- When was that?
- About a week before she went missing.
You don't think he did it, do you?
I mean, he's a cop.
- A cop? Do you know his name?
- Yeah.
Officer Ray Moran, San Francisco P.D.
Beat cop.
All right, talk to his captain.
See if we can bring Moran in
for an interview.
Put Cho on it.
Jane, too, if he ever comes in.
You got it.
Hey, boss?
I did it. I made it
into the program.
White Hat? You got in?
That's great.
Yeah. A month in L.A.
I'll be staring at a computer screen
the whole time but still.
The team's gonna miss you.
You said you'd talk to Bertram
about the stipend request.
The deposit's due in two days.
- I'll swing by on my way back.
- Thanks, boss.
"It's called White Hat."
It's an advanced computer
investigation training program
taught by actual hackers.
It's so advanced, I don't know what
she's saying when she talks about it.
I'd like to rush a request for a training
stipend to cover the costs.
You think Manchester's
been cheating?
- What?
- At poker.
No.
Well, he's just so damn smug.
You know, "Goodnight Moon," he says...
- what the hell is that?
- It's just a game.
You don't believe that.
Sir...
- No...oh, what was that about Van Pelt?
- Her training stipend.
Times are tight.
We've cut all outside
training funds from the budget.
No, request denied.
Hey.
- Lisbon said she lost you.
- Well, I come bearing gifts.
Grace.
Jelly dinosaurs are for me...
for later.
And...
- I'm guessing you're a Triceratops man.
- Yeah.
Rigsby is a T. Rex.
Any news on the case?
Yeah, the victim's ex-boyfriend
is an S.F.P.D. beat cop.
He's on patrol right now.
I was just gonna go talk to him.
- On the streets?
- Yeah.
Let's go. I haven't been
on the streets for a while.
Let's do it.
- Come on.
- Thanks?
I don't know. He was like, uh, 5'6".
Not fat, really. Just a big face.
Brown hair.
He didn't even have a gun.
Why'd you give him the money?
I didn't give it to him,
he took it!
What was he dressed like,
this guy?
You guys from CBI?
Agent Cho.
This is Patrick Jane.
Uh, look, I want to talk to you guys
but we gotta handle this, okay?
Let me catch up with you
in a couple hours.
- A couple hours?
- Yeah, we just got this.
I mean, we gotta put out a crime broadcast.
We gotta cruise the neighborhood.
Then there's the paperwork.
Well, can't help you
with the paperwork.
- He had a hood. He came in...
- Why'd you give him the money?
Sir, we're asking
the questions here.
Just tell me what happened.
So this dude comes up
while I'm cashing out the register
asks for a calling card.
I just turned for one second
and he reached through the gap
and grabbed a stack of $20s.
You wait until you're finished cashing out
before you do another transaction!
Look, the guy had money.
He didn't look shady or anything.
- How was I supposed to know?
- Hey. Excuse me.
Show me how he reached
through the gap again.
All right.
Pull your hand out.
Huh?
That's how they catch a raccoon,
you know that?
So the guy couldn't have grabbed
the cash through the gap.
There wasn't another guy,
was there, buddy?
- You! You're the thief!
- I'm the thief?
You're the thief.
With what you're paying me,
I'm the thief?
Work's done here, buddy.
I think you can get your man
to do the paperwork.
Look...
no, no, no.
When did you
and Linda meet?
Last year. I was moonlighting
doing security at the museum.
And how was the relationship?
Her life was more together
than anybody I ever met.
She was so focused.
Got to me, too, I guess.
I even started studying
for the sergeant's exam.
And then you dumped her?
- You think I was happy about it?
- You tell me.
About two months ago
I got an anonymous e-mail
with a link in it
to her online dating profile.
I couldn't believe it.
And she'd started
seeing other people?
I... I don't know
if she started.
She was just shopping around.
Maybe she'd been doing it
the whole time.
- You talk to her about it?
- Yeah.
Big fight.
You get rough with her?
I don't have that in me.
Hurt a woman?
Especially not Linda.
She have an explanation?
She denied it, you know,
but what else was she gonna do?
I can't take cheating.
I had to let her go.
- Did you know who sent you the profile?
- No.
And you weren't curious?
I don't know. I...
Some guy's girlfriend's
in the same boat as me
somebody's holding a grudge.
Only thing that mattered
was I wasn't enough for her.
And after you broke up,
you never spoke to her again?
No.
I should have known.
You know, she had smarts.
She was gonna have a big life.
What'd she want
with a mook like me, right?
Do you have something?
Here's the dating profile
somebody sent Moran.
Get a hold of the dating site.
See if anybody contacted her
around the time
she went missing.
- I don't think Linda went on any dates.
- Well, why not?
The address that sent Moran the e-mail
was used to set up an account
with the dating site.
- Did you find them?
- Sort of. I logged into the account.
Don't you need a password for that?
I spent two minutes using
the most common passwords.
- It was "qwerty."
- "Qwerty"?
Q-w-e-r-t-y.
It's the fifth most
common password.
- Guess whose profile it was.
- Linda.
So whoever sent Moran the profile
also created it.
Yep. Profile's a fake.
Someone was trying to break up
Linda and Officer Moran.
Nice work.
Look, I know you're disappointed
about the training program.
- We'll get you in next year.
- It's fine.
Bertram's supposed to be
this real smooth player
but he loses a couple of hands of poker
and he has to bum everybody else out.
Linda wanted
"a man with a super hot body."
- The fake dating profile, right?
- You were saying something?
Bertram hanging Van Pelt out to dry.
He's just mad because
he's losing big money at poker.
Well, some people like to push
their pain onto other people
weaker people, and there's
always someone weaker.
- That's just the circle of life.
- Cheery.
Bertram doesn't want to win,
Lisbon, he has to.
It's why he is where he is.
The idea of losing
is just intolerable to him.
Why would somebody want to break
Linda and her boyfriend up?
- Romantic rivalry?
- Yeah, possibly.
"I'm looking for brains,
brawn, the total package."
Van Pelt's trying to trace the e-mail
but she hit a dead end.
Well, whoever authored this
left their fingerprints all over it.
"No half-steppers."
"A genuine badass."
"Feather my nest."
- Gather the troops, Lisbon.
- Why?
It's time to play bingo.
So we have a list of words
from the fake dating profile.
We talk to the students
and compare what they say
to the words in the list
and if what they say matches up
with the words on the list
then they're the one
that wrote the profile?
So far, so good.
But how do we get them
to say the right words?
What do we ask them about?
You have to try to get
their words flowing.
- Talk to them about their passions.
- Their passions?
Animals, of course.
Bugs. Critters.
People use "coldblooded" to mean evil
as if a specie's thermo-physiology
could determine its moral attributes.
That's ridiculous.
Reptiles never invented
the atomic bomb.
If you ask me, warm blood
is the problem.
Know what I mean?
Excuse me.
So... skeletons.
Why are you into them?
Why do I need a reason?
I'll just go with "weird."
It's, like, under all this viscera
we wear
there's...well,
there's something strong
and...and clean and...and beautiful
that...that holds us together.
You can't lose it.
I think...I think that's cool.
Did I pass?
I've taken a psych test before.
Mr. Jane.
We were just discussing you.
Dean Papadakis told me
about your impressive memory.
My own memory isn't as good
as it used to be.
What's your secret?
It's easy to remember
when you never forget.
- What you doing?
- Laying bait for moths.
They like sweetness
so I use brown bananas and beer.
Delicious.
Paul here discovered
a new species of moth.
The California Jade moth.
It's on display in our museum.
It's rather a big deal.
Yeah. Now there are 1,500,001
types of insects in the world.
Well, that's false modesty.
I guess so. It is a big deal.
To moth people.
To all of us.
Congratulations
on your new addition.
- Thank you.
- It's most impressive.
Thank you.
Uh, let me guess.
You're studying buzzards and
you're laying a trap for one right now.
As if.
Mating habits
of the zalophus californianus.
Sea lions.
One badass male maintaining
a stable of females through combat.
Huh. And that appeals to you?
A man fighting for you?
Who doesn't want an Alpha male?
A guy who will fight for what's his?
Yeah. Super hot.
Sounds exciting.
It's so cool.
While Paul chases moths
and Jeanette messes around
with her lizards
I head out for the islands
to watch the seals play.
I'm not just a brain, see?
I like to play, too.
I'm the total package.
"Badass", "super-hot",
"total package."
Bingo!
Whoo! Bingo!
You wrote the fake
dating profile
that made Linda and her
boyfriend break up.
No law against it, is there?
Maybe she found out it was you
confronted you in the lab,
and things got out of hand.
Look... hello!
I didn't kill Linda.
So why did you want
to break them up?
You don't even know
what it's like in the program.
Dr. Kidd likes us to play
like we're one happy family.
We're like a pack of hyenas
tearing each other apart.
- Why?
- Money. Why else?
Look, the museum doesn't get
all that stuff for free.
It needs discoveries,
publicity, donations.
Dr. Kidd wants our program
to be the best.
So if you aren't producing,
so long.
What does that mean?
You ever heard of
survival of the fittest?
'Cause Dr. Kidd sure has.
She likes to weed out the ones
who can't contribute
who can't hack it.
But nobody hacks it.
Not really.
What do you mean?
Jeanette? Lizard girl?
She has a special place on the
back stairs where she goes to cry.
Greg had a major breakdown last year
like throwing rat skulls out the window.
And Paul? He was convinced
Dr. Kidd was gonna fire him
until he discovered
that dumb moth.
How about Linda?
How did she handle it?
She was a machine.
You're losing your mind
and there she is working just as hard,
not even breaking a sweat.
My mom wanted to kill me
for not getting the Dean's fellowship.
And then Linda lands
that hot cop boyfriend?
Her?
I mean...
Right?
So you made up the fake dating profile
to break them up.
I just wanted to see
if I could hurt her.
- If she could even be hurt.
- Did she know it was you?
It wrecked her.
The next day she messed up something stupid
and Dr. Kidd yelled at her.
You know what?
It felt really, really good.
And I know that doesn't make me sound
like a nice person.
No. No, it doesn't.
It's like "Lord of the Flies" over there.
I didn't know the world of science
was so cutthroat.
Well, like the man said
academic politics can be vicious,
because the stakes are small.
Very small, indeed.
Tomorrow morning we need
to go back to the museum.
- Why?
- Education.
But now I have to do something.
And the A.G. knows damn well
the indictment won't stick.
I don't have time for this.
Nobody rides for free.
I mean, he knows that.
What... what, you came here
to play games?
I heard you've been losing
and, uh, it's been
affecting your work.
Uh, I'll call you back.
Look, the cards haven't been
falling my way.
Oh, come on.
You believe in luck?
No.
Lisbon says you're
pretty good.
Margaret, cancel my 6:00.
Two pair.
Four of a kind.
See?
- I know how to play poker.
- Of course you do.
You play the man,
not the cards.
Right? I know the odds,
I know myself.
You know people,
you know how to control them.
Not that you always care.
Uh... what's that mean?
Well, you win more flies
with honey than with vinegar
but you use vinegar anyway.
Is this about Lisbon?
You're very fond of
the fake tell, aren't you?
Before you bet, you look away
and you breathe out very slowly
like you're trying to...
calm yourself.
Yes.
Well, you have a tell
inside the fake tell.
When you're bluffing
the breathing is audible.
The hell it is.
I control myself.
You get yourself a good hand
and puff away like that
Manchester will for sure
think you're bluffing.
Trust me.
Mr. Jane.
Can I help you?
I hope so. Uh, you still want
to learn my memory trick?
I would.
Yeah, you teach a master class
with all of Linda's
fellow classmates, huh?
Paul and I will be teaching it
this afternoon.
Yeah.
Well, how about I put on a memory seminar
for you and your class?
That would be terrific.
But don't you have
a murder to solve?
Eh, all in good time.
I'm gonna need some tables
possibly three or four
across the back there.
Okay.
And, Linda's office
- it's full of animals... dead ones.
- It is.
We'll need access to that,
for props.
Okay. I assume...
That you have some ulterior motive
for all of this.
Do you have a suspect?
There's one thing I'd like you
to confirm for me.
What is that?
Just what is the diet of the northern
flicker woodpecker?
Yeah. Sure.
How can you like Triceratops
more than...
T. Rex?
T. Rex are losers.
Little arms. It's a big
chicken with teeth.
Yeah, and Triceratops
is basically a pig with horns.
And a shield on its head.
Beats a giant chicken
any day of the week.
In your dreams.
What did Jane want?
- He wants us back at the museum.
- What are we gonna do?
- Museum heist.
- Why?
I stopped asking questions
a long time ago. Come on.
What's this all about?
We just need to cover
our bases, sir.
What does this have to do
with the investigation?
I can't discuss ongoing details
of an investigation.
I'm gonna need to look
at one of these, uh, spiders.
The tarantulas?
Hey, kids, come check this out
spiders.
Uh yes, the tarantulas.
I don't see why it is necessary.
Don't worry, sir. This is,
official police business.
- Detective please.
- I assure you, it won't take too long.
Wait, what are you doing?
I'm gonna need to take
a close look at this...
- Spider here.
- No.
- This one specifically here, this spider.
- No, no, what are you doing?
- Don't pick it up.
- Here we go.
Just... no. Oh, oh, please.
Be very careful.
There we go.
Uh, yeah.
I don't see why this is necessary.
Don't worry children, it's...
- There we go.
- Wait, what are you doing?
Yeah, we're gonna have to, uh...
- Dust this for prints.
- Do what?
Pretty colors, ha kids?
Ow!
- Ow! Oh, ow! It bit me.
- Oh no! It bit him!
- Wait what?
- It bit me.
Let me call someone.
This seems dangerous.
- Hey...
- Ow! Ow! Look.
See? It's deadly.
It feels a little strange.
- I don't see anything.
- Oh, I'm feeling woozy.
No, I'm just kidding.
I'm fine.
Don't play with spiders, kids.
Okay?
We've got a real treat today.
You could call it
"evolution in action."
Mr. Patrick Jane
is coming to give us a seminar
on the upper limits of memory.
- Are we in the classroom?
- Yes, we are.
Great.
The human memory is far more capable
than most people realize.
I've been in this room once before.
But when I was in here...
I paid attention.
Very close attention.
Oh, thank you. Please.
But that's just memory 101.
Let's move forward
into the advanced coursework.
For memory to be useful
it has to be as accurate
and as fast as a camera.
- How many animals did you get, Lisbon?
- Around 30.
- And you got them from Linda's office?
- Yes, I did.
All of the animals
came from Linda's office.
That's a place
that I have never been.
And in a moment,
I will turn around
and look behind me...
and just for a few seconds...
and I will memorize every animal
on those tables in order.
And then I will show you
how you can do the same.
How do we know you didn't
already memorize them?
A skeptic. I should have known.
And you're right.
There's no reason
for you to trust me.
Paul, would you mind rearranging
the animals any way you see fit?
Sure.
Thank you.
The human brain.
Once you get it working right,
it can be incredibly effective.
The mind can do some
miraculous things.
Uh, like...
telling the future.
Which is what I'm doing
right now.
Bull.
For that...
You can be the one
who holds the prediction.
Science is about prediction,
isn't it?
Predictions based on
hard data, not fortunetelling.
Well, you say "tomato"
I say scientists believe
in rational thought.
And grids and lists
and classification
which is fine, but it's not
how the world works
and it's certainly not
how the brain works.
You're saying
people aren't rational?
Well, being rational is a tool
but it's not the only tool we have.
Long before we stuffed our knowledge
into graphs and charts
we used older and, in some cases
more entertaining ways
to remember things.
- How we doing there, Paul?
- I think we're good.
Excellent. Please, take a seat.
Now, I'd like to show you
what I'm talking about.
Lisbon, uh, would you mind?
Thank you.
We can create a memory
by building a palace
in our minds.
We can sing ourselves a song
or tell ourselves
a little story.
A story of a bully...
a gray fox...
and a little brave man...
a rat...
that stood up for his chubby
little buddy the toad
and his friend egghead.
The story of a man in a tuxedo
who snaked his way through a crowd
to meet a woman
in a colorful dress.
Penguin, cobra,
three squirrels, and a parrot.
The story of flight...
An owl, a bat, a moth, all...
I sense I made a mistake.
No moth.
Well, perhaps my prediction
will explain my error.
Uh, Jeanette,
could you read it out, please?
- "The moth is in Paul's pocket"?
- Wait, what?
The moth.
The moth you stole
from the table
when you were rearranging
the animals...
it's in your pocket.
I'm gonna need you to empty
your pockets.
Come on.
Let's have a look.
Paul, why did you
take the moth?
- That's a California Jade moth.
- So it is.
The kind he discovered.
I thought the only other one
was in the museum.
Where did that come from?
Wait a second.
You said all the animals
came from Linda's office.
They did.
Linda died before
Paul discovered the moth.
This moth couldn't have come
from her... office.
You'll get there.
Unless...
She discovered the moth first.
Paul...
- You didn't kill Linda.
- Yes, he did.
But, uh, I confess...
that moth didn't come
from Linda's office. I...
S... well, I-I borrowed it
from the museum...
to prove a point.
Paul.
I'd just had a paper rejected.
Peer review
threw it back at me.
Dr. Kidd was so disappointed.
She never said anything.
She never had to.
How did Linda come into it?
"It was late night at the lab."
"Uh, she came in fresh
from the forest, excited."
"She'd seen one of her
woodpeckers eating a moth"
"that she couldn't identify."
So she put down some bait
and caught one.
We found the brown sugar
in her office.
- Was that her bait?
- Yeah.
I knew what it was
the moment I saw it.
"A new species."
"I mean, that's articles
that's museum exhibits"
that's money
for the program.
I saw myself naming the moth.
"I'd...I'd always wanted
to name something."
"My job was on the line."
"My future."
"I needed it..."
To survive.
I just lost myself completely.
"I came back to my senses.
I cleaned up."
"Lots of ways to clean up blood in the lab."
"And then, I gave Linda to the warms."
Then I went out to the part of the forest
where I knew she'd been.
Discovered the moth.
I came back
and got my accolades.
I saved my job.
I got everything I wanted.
Dr. Kidd.
Sonia, please.
I wanted to thank you
for catching Paul.
There's no thanks necessary.
Linda's dead, Paul's in jail
and Megan is being expelled.
I don't think the program
will ever recover.
The program isn't real.
The question is,
will you recover?
I felt so powerless.
I mean, what can you do
in the face of death?
You're not powerless, though.
You act.
Well, there's one thing
you can do.
Uh... Paul took a lot of pride
in naming that moth, when...
When it should have been
Linda who named it.
Yes.
I'll make sure to rename it
after her.
Thank you.
Pleasure.
Yeah.
Makes sense.
- All the good ones are taken.
- Please.
- Natural selection, I suppose.
- Come on.
Good-bye, Patrick.
Good-bye, Sonia.
$500 to Dawkins.
Nope.
I'll, uh...
Raise $100.
Well, I'm just gonna have to
raise you another $100.
When are you gonna learn, Gale?
Well...
Raise $1,000.
All in.
Two pair.
Flush.
Flush takes the pot.
"Goodnight Moon."
"Goodnight Stars."
"Goodnight Judge."
You see that?
Did you see that?
The flush?
It was very nice.
Ah, I gutted him!
I would say so, yeah.
That was very slick,
you having Jane give me lessons.
You must really want to help
Van Pelt.
What did Jane do?
Oh, now there's no need
to be coy.
I don't have a problem
with a little quid pro quo.
The White Hat program,
wasn't it?
I'll authorize the stipend
in the morning.
- Thank you, sir.
- No, no. Thank you.
- And thank Jane.
- I will.
And some scientists think the T. Rex
could run up to 45 miles an hour.
That's apex predator.
- You know what that means?
- Yes.
That means they're
top of the food chain.
- They eat everything.
- So?
So... T. Rex beats
Triceratops. I win.
You went home last night
and Googled dinosaurs
- didn't you?
- Yeah, I did.
You have no life. I win.
I owe her from yesterday.
She's on her way
to the airport.
Oh. Yeah, for that
White Hat thing.
I thought there was
no money for that.
Lisbon fixed it.
Would have been nice
to say good-bye.
Yeah, well, cowards don't get
to say good-bye when they want.
Cow... wow.
Where'd that come from?
- You calling me a coward?
- Yep.
How so?
How long have you been pretending
you're not in love with Van Pelt?
Who says I'm in love
with Van Pelt?
I was once, a long time ago,
but not anymore.
We're just...
We're just... good friends.
You're a coward
and terrible liar.
Says you.
"Coward." What does he know
about relationships?
Yeah, well, you date
pregnant hookers
and your...
your dinosaur eats grass!
- Morning.
- Good morning.
We're gonna be short-staffed for a while.
Van Pelt's off to L.A.
Thank you.
Adult education's
a beautiful thing.
Speaking of which, uh...
I've upset the ecosystem
of the poker game.
I think you've been spending
too much time at the museum.
"Upset the ecosystem"?
Bertram's now a better poker player
because of me.
The ecosystem has changed.
You need to adapt or die.
Who says I need the help?
Don't try to razzle-dazzle me.
Money talks.
What do we use for stakes?
You can't play poker without stakes.
Oh, I have that covered.
Herbivores are worth 1,
carnivores are worth 5.
Okay.
Deal.
What do you got?
- All in.
- You're bluffing. I call.
Really?
- Okay, are you cheating?
- No.
Wh...
I'm gonna smoke you.